[ Man ] ALREADY CHECKED CORRIDOR 2. NOTHING THERE. [ Man #2 ] ANYTHING AT ALL?
已经检查过2号走廊了。 那儿什么也没有。 发现什么了吗？
WHERE IS HE? FIND HIM!
他在哪儿？ 找到他！
[ Buzzer Blaring ] COME ON, GO! LET'S GO!
[警报大作] 快，走！ 动起来！
[ Buzzer Sounding, Helicopter Whirring ]
[警报声，直升机轰鸣声]
[ Ship's Horn Sounding ]
[船只鸣笛声]
♪♪ [ Man Vocalizing "Jingle Bells" ]
[男人哼唱《铃儿响叮当》]
[ Man ] WELL, I GUESS MAMA WON'T BE KISSING SANTA CLAUS THIS YEAR.
好吧，看来妈妈今年 亲不到圣诞老人了。 注：引用圣诞歌曲《I Saw Mommy Kissing Santa Claus》。
JUST TELL ME WHAT YOU SAW.
告诉我你看到了什么。
HEY, I'M JUST AN ELF. I DO WHAT I'M TOLD. YOU KNOW?
嘿，我只是个小精灵。 我只是听命行事，懂吗？
"BE JOLLY"? BESIDES, I HAVEN'T SEEN THE BIG GUY SINCE THE PARTY LAST NIGHT.
“要保持快乐”？况且， 自从昨晚的派对后 我就没见过这位大人物。
OH, YEAH? WHEN ARE YOU GONNA SHOVEL HIM OUT?
噢，是吗？ 你打算什么时候 帮他铲雪？
SOON ENOUGH. THE MEAT WAGON JUST GOT HERE.
快了。 运尸车 刚到。
DON'T YOU MEAN THE "MEAT SLEIGH"? HO, HO, HO.
你是指 “运尸雪橇”吗？ 吼，吼，吼。
HEY. [ Cop ] EVENIN'.
嘿。 晚上好。
OKAY. GOT A LIVE ONE.
好了，有个“活的”。 注：警察的冷笑话，指发现了一具尸体。
- A LIVE ONE? - IT'S A JOKE.
- 一个活的？ - 开个玩笑。
SNOWBLOWERS MUST HAVE BURIED HIM.
肯定是扫雪机 把他埋了。
[ Jarod ] IS THAT... SANTA CLAUS?
那是…… 圣诞老人吗？
YEAH. THE RED HAT'S A DEAD GIVEAWAY.
是啊。那顶红帽子 暴露了身份。
ANYBODY GOT A SHOVEL? NO.
有人带铲子了吗？ 没有。
BUT I'VE GOT THE GIFT WRAP.
但我带了包装纸。
[ Man Narrating ]
[旁白]
THANKS, GUS.
多谢，古斯。
DR. DRAKE? THESE JUST CAME IN FROM THE MAYOR'S OFFICE.
德雷克医生？这些是 市长办公室刚送来的。
- SAME GIFT AS LAST YEAR? - SMELLS LIKE IT.
- 跟去年的礼物一样？ - 闻着像。
OH, WELL. 'TIS THE SEASON, FUGIMORA.
噢，好吧。 佳节将至，藤森。
PASS 'EM OUT. WE'LL SEE WHO SURVIVES THIS YEAR.
发下去吧。 看看今年 谁能挺过去。
YES, MA'AM.
好的，女士。
- UH, SO, HOW'S THE NEW GUY DOIN'? - A LOT BETTER THAN SANTA.
- 呃，那个 新来的怎么样？ - 比圣诞老人强多了。
DRINKING ON THE JOB? ACTUALLY, THIS WAS FROM THE SCENE.
上班时间喝酒？ 其实，这是 现场的证物。
DR. JAROD MARLEY? MEET DR. LISABETH DRAKE, OUR CHIEF CORONER.
JAROD·马利医生？ 这位是伊丽莎白·德雷克医生， 我们的首席法医。
HELLO. HI. YOU FINISHED WITH ST. NICK?
你好。 你好。处理完圣尼古拉斯了？
- YES, I AM. - [ Man Clearing Throat ]
- 是的，处理完了。 - [清嗓子声]
DETECTIVE GUERRA. GEE, RIGHT ON TIME.
盖拉警探。 哟，真准时。
- NOW, CAN WE DO THIS? - VICTIM IS NOT KRISS KRINGLE,
- 现在可以开始了吗？ - 受害者不是圣诞老人，
AS WE FIRST SUSPECTED, BUT A THEODORE HARGROVE,
正如我们最初怀疑的那样， 而是西奥多·哈格罗夫，
58, STOCKBROKER, PLAYED SANTA AT ONE HELL OF A CHRISTMAS PARTY DOWNTOWN.
58岁，股票经纪人， 昨晚在市区的一场 圣诞狂欢派对上扮演圣诞老人。
GO AHEAD, DOCTOR. HE DIED OF A COMBINATION OF FACTORS, MAINLY A HEART ATTACK.
继续吧，医生。 他死于多种因素， 主要是心脏病发作。
KIM, I THOUGHT WE WERE GOING WITH EXPOSURE.
金，我以为我们要 判定为冻死。
WELL, THAT WAS MY FIRST INSTINCT, BUT FURTHER EXAMINATION REVEALED THE TRUTH.
那是我的第一直觉， 但进一步 检查揭示了真相。
HEART ATTACK MAKES SENSE. FOLKS AT THE OFFICE PARTY SAID ST. NICK WAS DOIN'...
心脏病发作很合理。 办公室派对的人说 这位圣诞老人当时正跳着……
- ONE HELL OF A LAMBADA THAT NIGHT. - I DON'T KNOW WHO "LAMBADA" IS,
- 极其火辣的 兰巴达舞。 - 我不知道“兰巴达”是谁，
BUT, YES, LIVIDITY WAS AFFECTED BY THE COLD.
但是，是的，尸斑 确实受到了寒冷的影响。
BUT THE BLOOD DISTRIBUTION IN THE LEG MUSCLES WOULD SUGGEST HE WAS DOING STRENUOUS ACTS.
但腿部肌肉的 血液分布表明 他当时在做剧烈运动。
WHAT ABOUT TIME OF DEATH? [ Dr. Drake ] NO WAY.
死亡时间呢？ 没戏。
WE CAN'T PULL THAT OFF IN THIS WEATHER.
在这种天气下 根本测不准。
ACTUALLY, THAT'S WHERE THIS CAME IN.
实际上，这就 派上用场了。
THE EGGNOG WAS HARD WHEN WE FOUND IT, BUT IT WASN'T COMPLETELY FROZEN THROUGH.
我们发现蛋奶酒时 它已经变硬了， 但还没完全冻透。
MAINLY BECAUSE MR. HARGROVE HAD QUITE A BIT OF BRANDY IN IT.
主要是因为哈格罗夫先生 在里面加了不少白兰地。
- OH, THERE'S A SHOCKER. - THE MILK HAD TIME TO CURDLE.
- 噢，真让人意外。 - 牛奶有时间凝固。
SO I COMPARED THE BACTERIA LEVELS IN THE CUP...
所以我对比了 杯子里的细菌含量……
WITH THAT OF THE SAMPLE THAT FELL ON THE SNOW,
以及 洒在雪地上的样本，
AND I DEDUCED THAT MR. HARGROVE SUCCUMBED TO HIS HEART ATTACK...
我推断哈格罗夫先生 死于心脏病的时间……
SOMEWHERE BETWEEN 1:45 AND 2:00 A.M.
是在凌晨 1:45到2:00之间。
MY GUESS WOULD BE 1:48-ISH.
我猜是 1:48左右。
- [ Whistles ] - I ASK FOR AN AUTOPSY, HE GIVES ME EGGNOG.
- [吹口哨] - 我要验尸报告， 他给我整出杯蛋奶酒。
[ Phone Ringing ]
[电话铃响]
YEP? OKAY.
喂？好的。
DR. DRAKE? THE DELEGATION FROM THE MAYOR'S OFFICE IS HERE.
德雷克医生？市长办公室的 代表团到了。
DAMN! THEY'RE EARLY. WE'RE DONE HERE.
该死！他们来早了。 我们这儿完事了。
- CAREER ANXIETY? - OH, YOU HAVEN'T MET THE MAYOR.
- 职业焦虑？ - 噢，你还没见过市长呢。
BUT, HEY, HE GIVES KILLER CHRISTMAS PRESENTS--
不过，嘿，他送的 圣诞礼物很棒——
AND I MEAN... KILLER.
我是说……简直要命。
[ Groaning ] NO, NOT AGAIN!
[呻吟] 不，又来了！
- IS THIS FOR ME? - GEEZ, JAROD, DON'T TELL ME...
- 这是给我的吗？ - 天呐，JAROD，别告诉我……
YOU NEVER GOT A CHRISTMAS PRESENT BEFORE.
你以前从没 收到过圣诞礼物。
NOT IN A VERY LONG TIME. THANK YOU.
很久没有过了。 谢谢。
A PASTRY WITH CANDIED CHERRIES.
一种加了糖渍樱桃的面点。
IT'S FRUITCAKE.
那是水果蛋糕。
A CAKE WITH FRUIT BAKED RIGHT IN.
一种把水果 直接烤在里面的蛋糕。
THANK YOU. THIS HAS TO BE DELICIOUS.
谢谢。 这一定很好吃。
[ Woman On P.A. ] RECORDS DEPARTMENT, PLEASE CALL THE THIRD FLOOR.
[广播] 档案部， 请给三楼回电。
SHOULD WE TELL HIM? LET HIM DISCOVER IT.
我们要告诉他吗？ 让他自己去发现吧。
YEAH.
也是。
MMM!
嗯！
♪♪ [ Christmas Carol ]
[圣诞颂歌]
JAROD HAS BEEN MOVED TO HIS ROOM.
JAROD已经被 移回他的房间了。
AS ALWAYS, I BEGIN MY CHRISTMAS HIATUS TOMORROW.
一如既往，我明天 开始我的圣诞假期。
I'LL BE IN MOUNT PLEASANT AT THE USUAL NUMBER.
我会待在普莱森特山， 拨打平时的号码。
IT IS THE CHRISTMAS SEASON.
现在是圣诞季节。
BUT THE TOWER DEEMS IT BEST TO INSULATE JAROD...
但塔楼认为最好 让JAROD与世隔绝……
FROM THE TRAPPINGS OF POPULAR CULTURE.
远离流行文化的 那些诱惑。
[ Young Sydney ] JAROD, I'LL BE GONE FOR THE WEEK,
[年幼的悉尼] JAROD，我要 离开一周，
AND I WANTED TO SAY GOOD-BYE.
我是来 跟道别的。
WHY DO YOU GO AWAY EVERY YEAR WHEN IT TURNS COLD OUTSIDE?
为什么每年外面 变冷的时候你都要离开？
BUSINESS, JAROD. THAT'S ALL.
公事，JAROD。仅此而已。
IF YOU CAN KEEP A SECRET, I BROUGHT YOU A LITTLE SOMETHING.
如果你能保密，我 给你带了点小东西。
A GIFT.
一份礼物。
A GIFT?
一份礼物？
- THIS IS SNOW. - YES. REMEMBER.
- 这是雪。 - 是的。记住。
-TELL NO ONE I GAVE THIS TO YOU. -TAKE ME OUTSIDE, SYDNEY.
- 别告诉任何人我给了你这个。 - 带我出去吧，悉尼。
- TO SEE THE REAL SNOW. - I CAN'T, JAROD.
- 去看看真正的雪。 - 我不能，JAROD。
BUT I WANT TO SEE IT FOR MYSELF. ENJOY THIS SNOW.
但我想要 亲眼去看看。 享受这些雪吧。
AND I WILL SEE YOU AGAIN SOON.
我们很快 就会再见的。
WHAT, ARE YOU WRITING A BOOK?
怎么，你是在 写书吗？
UM, NO, NOT EXACTLY.
呃，不，不完全是。
[ Sighs ] YOU MISS HIM, DON'T YOU?
[叹气] 你很想念他，对吧？
WHO? GEORGE. CHRISTMAS GEORGE.
谁？ 乔治。 圣诞乔治。
YOU KNEW GEORGE? I FEEL LIKE I DID.
你认识乔治？ 我感觉我认识他。
GEORGE WAS ALL THE FAMILY I HAD.
乔治 是我唯一的家人。
WELL, HE WAS ALL THE FAMILY A LOT OF PEOPLE HAD.
好吧，他是 很多人的唯一家人。
THE CHILDREN AT THE SHELTER MISS HIM. YEAH. FOSTER KIDS, RUNAWAYS--
收容所的 孩子们都很想念他。 是啊。寄养儿童，离家出走的孩子——
THEY KNEW THE REAL GEORGE. OH, EVERYBODY THOUGHT HE WAS A BUM,
他们知道真正的乔治。 噢，大家都 以为他是个流浪汉，
BECAUSE HE DIDN'T HAVE A HOME AND PANHANDLED TO GET BY.
因为他没家， 靠乞讨过活。
BUT HE TOOK ALL THAT MONEY, AND ONE DAY A YEAR,
但他把所有的钱都攒下来， 一年里的那一天，
HE MADE SURE THEY HAD PRESENTS AND A SPECIAL MEAL.
他会确保他们有 礼物和一顿丰盛的大餐。
EVERY CHRISTMAS EVE, HE'D DRESS AS SANTA...
每年平安夜， 他都会扮成圣诞老人……
AND READ TO THOSE KIDS ALL NIGHT LONG.
整晚给 那些孩子读书。
THAT'S WHY THEY CALLED HIM CHRISTMAS GEORGE.
这就是为什么大家都叫他 圣诞乔治。
YEAH. WHEN GEORGE WAS ALIVE,
是啊。 当乔治还在世时，
THEY ALL HAD FAMILY FOR AT LEAST ONE DAY.
他们至少在那一天 拥有了家人。
CHRISTMAS DOESN'T COUNT FOR SQUAT WITHOUT FAMILY, SON.
没有家人的圣诞节 根本毫无意义，孩子。
NO.
是的。
I'M BEGINNING TO REALIZE THAT.
我也开始 意识到这一点了。
[ Woman ] OH, THERE YOU ARE, JAROD.
[女人] 噢，你在这儿啊，JAROD。
I JUST WANTED TO THANK YOU FOR ALL THE WORK YOU'VE DONE THIS SEASON.
我只是想谢谢你 这个季节 所做的一切工作。
WITHOUT CHRISTMAS GEORGE, IT HASN'T BEEN THE SAME.
没有了圣诞乔治， 一切都变得不一样了。
OH, I'M HAPPY TO HELP.
噢，我很乐意帮忙。
FOR A HAPPY MAN, YOU LOOK PERPLEXED.
作为一个快乐的人， 你看起来挺困惑的。
WELL, THE TRUTH IS, I AM.
好吧，实话实说，我确实很困惑。
- HAVE YOU READ THIS? - [ Chuckles ] "THE NIGHT BEFORE CHRISTMAS"?
- 你读过这个吗？ - [轻笑] 《圣诞前夜》？
IT'S A CLASSIC! IT'S VERY GOOD, BUT I'M A LITTLE CONFUSED ABOUT SOMETHING.
那可是经典！ 它写得很好，但我对 某些事情有点困惑。
NOW, IF SANTA CLAUS WERE TO DELIVER A PRESENT TO EVERY CHILD ON EARTH,
如果圣诞老人 要给地球上的 每个孩子送礼物，
HE'D HAVE TO VISIT 830 HOMES A SECOND.
他一秒钟内 得拜访830个家庭。
WHICH WOULD MEAN HIS REINDEER WOULD HAVE TO TRAVEL ABOUT 700 MILES PER SECOND,
这意味着他的驯鹿 飞行速度得达到 每秒约700英里，
AND HE'D HAVE 1/1000th OF A SECOND TO PARK THE SLEIGH,
而且他只有千分之一秒 的时间来停好雪橇，
TO CRAWL DOWN THE CHIMNEY, TO PASS OUT THE PRESENTS AND TO EAT COOKIES AND MILK.
爬下烟囱， 分发礼物， 还要吃掉饼干和牛奶。
AND FOR A MIDDLE-AGED, OVERWEIGHT MAN, THAT'S QUITE A FEAT.
对于一个中年 肥胖男人来说， 这简直是项壮举。
[ Chuckles ] SANTA WORKS IN MYSTERIOUS WAYS.
[轻笑] 圣诞老人自有 他的神力。
BUT IT'S SO FANTASTICAL. WHY WOULD ANYBODY BELIEVE IT?
但这太不可思议了。 为什么会有人相信呢？
IT'S CHRISTMAS, JAROD. ANYTHING'S POSSIBLE.
现在是圣诞节，JAROD。 奇迹无处不在。
OH. [ Laughs ]
噢。 [笑声]
ANGEL, THEY'RE GETTING READY TO STRING SOME POPCORN.
安吉尔，他们正准备 串爆米花呢。
DON'T YOU WANT TO HELP?
你不想去帮忙吗？
DON'T YOU WANT TO TALK TO SANTA?
你不想 去跟圣诞老人说话吗？
HE'S NOT SANTA. IS SOMETHING WRONG?
他不是圣诞老人。 出什么事了吗？
IS CHRISTMAS GEORGE COMING BACK?
圣诞乔治 还会回来吗？
NO. NO, HE ISN'T.
不。不，他不回来了。
WHY NOT?
为什么？
CHRISTMAS GEORGE DIED.
圣诞乔治去世了。
DO YOU KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS?
你知道这意味着什么吗？
WE WON'T EVER SEE HIM AGAIN.
我们再也 见不到他了。
WELL, THAT'S TRUE, AND THEN AGAIN, IT ISN'T.
嗯，你说得对， 但也不全对。
COULD I ASK YOU SOMETHING?
我能问你个问题吗？
WHY DID YOU LIKE CHRISTMAS GEORGE?
你为什么 喜欢圣诞乔治？
SOMETHING UNDER THE TREE ON CHRISTMAS.
圣诞树下 总会有惊喜。
SO WHAT YOU'RE SAYING IS THAT HE HAD A SPIRIT, A FEELING, THAT MADE YOU FEEL GOOD.
所以你的意思是， 他带给你一种 精神，一种感觉， 让你觉得很温暖。
WELL, AS LONG AS YOU HAVE THAT FEELING, CHRISTMAS GEORGE IS GONNA BE RIGHT HERE.
那么，只要你保留 那种感觉， 圣诞乔治就 永远活在你心里。
SO EVERY TIME IT'S CHRISTMAS, I CAN THINK ABOUT GEORGE, AND HE'LL BE HERE?
所以每次过圣诞节， 我只要想到乔治， 他就会出现？
EVERY TIME.
每一次都会。
[ Chuckles ]
[轻笑]
CAN I HELP? [ Boy ] SURE. COME ON.
我能帮忙吗？ 当然。来吧。
♪♪ [ Violin: "O Holy Night" ]
[小提琴演奏《神圣之夜》]
♪♪ [ Continues ]
[音乐持续]
[ Dr. Fugimora ] GEEZ, JAROD. YOU'VE RUN 137 TESTS.
[藤森医生] 天呐，JAROD。 你已经跑了137次测试了。
ANY LUCK ON THE L.G.L.?
那个“迷途小女孩”有线索了吗？
- THAT'S NOT HER NAME. - I DIDN'T MEAN ANYTHING.
- 那不是她的名字。 - 我没别的意思。
SHE SHOULD HAVE A REAL NAME. HER FAMILY SHOULD KNOW.
她应该有 属于自己的名字。 她的家人应该知道真相。
ESPECIALLY AT THIS TIME OF THE YEAR.
尤其是在 这种时节。
YOU'RE NOT GONNA GIVE UP, ARE YOU?
你是不打算 放弃了，对吧？
[ Male Deejay ] AND WE'VE GOT MORE CHRISTMAS HITS COMING YOUR WAY, SO...
[电台男DJ] 我们还有更多 圣诞金曲送给您，所以……
SNUGGLE UP BY THE FIRE WITH THAT SPECIAL SOMEONE...
和那个特别的人 一起依偎在壁炉旁……
AND ENJOY THE HOLIDAY SEASON.
享受这个假期吧。
[ Ringing ]
[电话铃响]
WHAT? [ Man ] IT'S ME.
干嘛？ [男人] 是我。
I'M HAVING A HOLIDAY GATHERING AT THE CLUB.
我正在俱乐部 举办一场节日聚会。
IT WOULDN'T BE THE SAME WITHOUT MY FAVORITE GIRL.
要是没有我最心爱的女儿， 聚会就不完整了。
I'LL BE THERE. VERY WELL. CHRISTMAS EVE AT 7:00.
我会去的。 很好。 平安夜晚上7点。
SOME EUROPEAN ASSOCIATES WILL ATTEND. BE PROMPT. OF COURSE, DADDY.
会有一些欧洲的 合作伙伴出席。别迟到。 当然了，爸爸。
MERRY CHRIST-- [ Line Disconnects ]
圣诞快—— [挂断声]
[ Beeps ]
[哔声]
[ Woman On P.A., Indistinct ]
[广播里模糊的女声]
GUNSHOT WOUND TO THE GILL? [ Laughs ] NOT A PATIENT.
鱼鳃中弹了？ [大笑] 不是病人。
LUNCH. AREN'T YOU A LITTLE YOUNG FOR POISON FISH?
是午餐。 你吃这种毒鱼 是不是太年轻了点？
PUFFER FISH IS ONLY POISON BEFORE IT'S PREPARED. KIM.
河豚只有在 没处理好之前才有毒。 金。
FUGU TOXIN IS 500 TIMES STRONGER THAN CYANIDE. YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
河豚毒素的毒性 比氰化物强500倍。 知道啦，知道啦。
BUT WHEN IT'S DONE RIGHT, ALL YOU GET ARE TINGLY TOES AND A GREAT BUZZ.
但只要处理得当， 你只会感到脚趾发麻 还有一种飘飘然的感觉。
CHRISTMAS DINNER AROUND HERE. MY FUGU'S A TRADITION.
这是我们这儿的 圣诞晚餐传统。 我的河豚宴可是招牌。
THE BOYS IN THE MORGUE LOVE IT.
停尸房的伙计们 都爱死它了。
AND IT GOES GREAT WITH CRANBERRIES.
而且它和 蔓越莓是绝配。
I'LL STICK WITH FRUITCAKE.
我还是 吃水果蛋糕吧。
AND RELAX. MY UNCLE WAS A MASTER FUGU CHEF IN TOKYO.
放心吧。我叔叔 以前可是东京的 顶级河豚大厨。
- WAS? - HE'S RETIRED.
- 以前是？ - 他退休了。
[ Laughs ] OH, GOOD. WELL, I'M GLAD TO HEAR THAT.
[大笑] 噢，太好了。 很高兴听到这个。
UH, WOULD YOU HELP ME WITH THIS? MAN, DID YOU SPILL A WHOLE MUG?
呃，能帮我 处理一下这个吗？ 伙计，你洒了一整杯咖啡吗？
WELL, ACTUALLY, I SPILLED A WHOLE POT.
其实， 我洒了一整壶。
I'LL GET YOU A DUPLICATE. OH, NO, NO, NO. THAT'S OKAY.
我去给你弄份副本。 噢，不用了。 没关系。
JUST SHOW ME WHERE THE OLD FILES ARE.
带我去 旧档案室就行。
[ Chattering, Phones Ringing ] [ Woman ] YES, IT SHOULD TAKE A FEW SECONDS...
[杂谈声，电话铃响] [女人] 是的，应该 只需要几秒钟…… 就能起效。
YES, I'VE ALREADY DISPATCHED THE AMBULANCE.
是的，我已经 派出了救护车。
MA'AM-- MA'AM! NO.
女士——女士！不。
AN OVERFLOWING TOILET IS NOT A 911 CALL.
马桶溢水 并不是拨打911的理由。
MA'AM. WOULD YOU PLEASE HANG UP AND CALL A PLUMBER?
女士。请挂断电话 找个修理工好吗？
[ Speaking With Mouth Full ] OKAY. YOU NEED TO... INDUCE VOMITING.
[边吃边说] 好的。你需要…… 进行催吐。
YES. UH, NO, YOUR FINGER WILL BE FINE.
是的。呃，不， 你的手指会没事的。
YES. [ Man ] IT'S NOT WORKING. IT'S NOT WORKING.
是的。 [男人] 没用。 根本没用。
YOUR SON IS GOING TO BE FINE, MR. HODGES, IF YOU JUST LISTEN CAREFULLY.
你儿子会 没事的，霍奇斯先生， 只要你仔细听我说。
OKAY. [ Jarod ] NOW, REMEMBER, CLEAR THE AIRWAY...
好的。 [JAROD] 现在记住， 清理呼吸道……
AND TILT HIS HEAD BACK. RIGHT. TILT HIS HEAD BACK.
然后把他的头后仰。 对，把头后仰。
NOW BACK TO THE BREATHING. OKAY.
现在继续人工呼吸。 好的。
[ Beeping ]
[哔哔声]
[ Hodges ] OKAY. NOW CONTINUE THE UP AND DOWN MOTION ON HIS CHEST.
[霍奇斯] 好的。 现在继续在他胸口 规律按压。
OKAY. FIVE-COUNT? YES.
好的。数五下？ 是的。
[ Beeping ] [ Hodges ] OH, MY GOD. HE'S BREATHING!
[哔哔声] [霍奇斯] 噢，我的天呐。他有呼吸了！
- MY SON IS BREATHING! - THAT'S FANTASTIC, MR. HODGES.
- 我儿子有呼吸了！ - 太棒了，霍奇斯先生。
THEY'RE HERE! THE AMBULANCE JUST GOT HERE.
他们到了！ 救护车刚到。
YOU SEE? THAT WASN'T SO DIFFICULT.
你看？ 并没有那么难。
MERRY CHRISTMAS. THANK YOU SO MUCH. THANK YOU.
圣诞快乐。 非常感谢。 谢谢。
- [ Woman On Tape ] 911 OPERATOR. - HELLO. MY NAME'S HARRY.
- [录音带里的女声] 这里是911。 - 喂。我叫哈里。
I'M CALLING FROM THE CORNER OF LAWSON AND HILL.
我在劳森街 和希尔街的拐角打电话。
MY FRIEND-- OH, GOD, MY FRIEND GEORGE IS--
我的朋友——噢，上帝， 我的朋友乔治他——
[ Woman ] TELL ME WHAT THE PROBLEM IS, SIR. THEY RAN GEORGE DOWN.
[女人] 告诉我 出了什么问题，先生。 他们撞倒了乔治。
YOU GOTTA GET SOMEBODY DOWN HERE. LAWSON AND HILL.
你们得派人 过来。劳森街和希尔街。
RIGHT IN FRONT OF THE CHILDREN'S SHELTER.
就在 儿童收容所门前。
HURRY. YOU GOTTA HURRY. [ Operator ] I'M CALLING IT IN, SIR.
快点。你们得快点。 我正在派人过去，先生。
IS ANYONE ELSE HURT? NO, THEY JUST HIT HIM, AND THEY LEFT.
还有别人受伤吗？ 不，他们撞了他 就逃跑了。
I DIDN'T SEE NO CAR.
我没看清是什么车。
- THIS IS WHERE IT HAPPENED? - WHERE I FOUND HIM.
- 事情就是在这儿发生的？ - 就是在那儿我发现他的。
THEY JUST LEFT GEORGE THERE TO DIE.
他们就这样 把乔治丢在那儿 等死。
- "THEY"? - I DON'T KNOW. CRASH WOKE ME UP.
- “他们”是谁？ - 我不知道。 撞击声惊醒了我。
I DIDN'T SEE IT.
我没看见。
I'M SORRY.
我很遗憾。
I NEVER LEFT HIS SIDE. NEVER. NOT UNTIL THE CORONER SHOWED UP.
我一直守在他身边。 没离开过。直到 法医赶到。
THE CORONER? [ Sniffles ]
法医？ [抽鼻子声]
NOT THE POLICE?
不是警察先到吗？
BETTER DIRECTIONS, I GUESS.
法医认路更准吧，我想。
[ Sighs ] YOU KNOW, HE HELD MY HAND, AND--
[叹气] 你知道吗， 他握着我的手，然后——
AND WE GOT TO SAY GOOD-BYE.
我们总算 说了声再见。
YOU MEAN, HE DIDN'T DIE INSTANTLY?
你的意思是，他不是 当场死亡的？
AH, HELL NO. HE WAS A FIGHTER.
噢，见鬼，当然不是。 他是个硬汉。
CORONER TRIED TO SAVE HIM.
法医试着救他。
GAVE GEORGE A SHOT AND EVERYTHING, BUT--
还给乔治 打了一针什么的，但是——
DIDN'T HELP.
没起作用。
I NEVER KNEW CORONERS CARRIED DOCTOR BAGS.
我从不知道 法医还随身带 医药箱。
NEITHER DID I.
我也不知道。
SHE DID WHAT SHE COULD, I GUESS. BUT BY THE TIME THE COPS GOT HERE,
她尽力了， 我想。但等 警察赶到时，
SHE TOLD THEM GEORGE HAD PASSED. SHE?
她告诉他们 乔治已经断气了。 她？
WAS SHE ALONE? YEP.
她是一个人吗？ 是的。
AND SHE HAD RED HAIR. UH, YEAH.
而且她有一头红发。 呃，是的。
HOW'D YOU KNOW?
你怎么知道的？
[ Woman On P.A. ] ANY AVAILABLE ASSISTANCE TO THE I.V. UNIT.
[广播] 静脉注射室 需要人手。
WHY HAVEN'T YOU SHIPPED THE L.G.L.? WE NEED SLAB SPACE FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
为什么还没把 那个迷途小女孩 运走？节假日 停尸位很紧张。
I FOUND STRESS FRACTURES IN HER LEGS. FORGET ABOUT IT.
我在她的腿上 发现了应力性骨折。 别管那个了。
WE'VE DONE OUR DUE DILIGENCE.
我们已经 尽到职责了。
FINISH UP THE PAPERWORK AND SEND HER ALONG. I UNDERSTAND.
办好手续 赶紧把她送走。 我明白了。
BY THE WAY, NEW GUY WORKS CHRISTMAS EVE.
顺便说一下， 新来的 平安夜值班。
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT. LAST YEAR WAS SO SLOW, WE BROKE OUT A BOTTLE OF CHRISTMAS CHEER.
别担心。去年 那晚很清闲，我们还 开了一瓶 圣诞酒庆祝。
TOO BAD I WON'T BE HERE WITH YOU TO SHARE A TOAST.
可惜今年我 没法和你 一起举杯了。
WELL, YOU NEVER KNOW, DOCTOR. CHRISTMAS HAS ITS WAY OF BRINGING PEOPLE TOGETHER.
那可不一定，医生。 圣诞节总有办法 让人们团聚。
[ Jarod ] OUR JANE DOE'S REAL NAME IS GABRIELLE.
[JAROD] 我们这位 无名氏的真名 叫加布里埃尔。
GABRIELLE RYAN.
加布里埃尔·瑞安。
SHE'S FROM NASHTON. SHE WOULD HAVE BEEN 18 NEXT MONTH.
她是纳什顿人。 下个月 就满18岁了。
HOW'D YOU DO THIS?
你是怎么查出来的？
LOWER TIBIAL FRACTURES TO THE MEDIAL MALLEOLI.
胫骨下端 内踝骨折。
MEDIA WHO? BAD ANKLES.
内什么？ 脚踝受伤。
FROM COMPRESSION IMPACTS.
是由于 挤压撞击造成的。
THAT, AND SHE HAD CALLOUS PATTERNS ON HER HANDS LIKE THIS.
而且，她手上的 老茧分布是这样的。
PARALLEL BARS WERE HER SPECIALTY.
高低杠是 她的强项。
WILL YOU TELL HER FAMILY RIGHT AWAY?
你会立刻 通知她的家人吗？
COUNT ON IT.
当然。
HEY. GOOD WORK, JAROD.
嘿。干得好，JAROD。
SEE YOU AROUND.
回头见。
[ Women's Choir ] ♪ THIS POOR YOUNGLING ♪
[女声合唱团] 唱起这首歌……
♪ FOR WHOM WE DO SING ♪
送给这可怜的孩子……
♪ LULLY, LULLAY ♪
♪ 睡吧，睡吧 ♪
♪ THOU LITTLE TINY CHILD ♪
♪ 你这小小婴孩 ♪
♪ BY BY LULLY, LULLAY ♪
♪ 睡吧，宝贝，睡吧 ♪
♪ LULLAY, THOU LITTLE ♪
♪ 睡吧，你这小小 ♪
♪ TINY CHILD ♪
♪ 小小婴孩 ♪
FACE IT, SYDNEY. IT'S ALMOST CHRISTMAS. ♪ BY BY LULLY ♪
面对现实吧，悉尼。 马上就到圣诞节了。
HE'S NOT GOING TO CALL. ♪ LULLAY ♪
他不会打电话来的。
[ Sighs ] I SEE YOU'RE CLEARING OUT FOR YOUR USUAL HOLIDAY HIATUS,
[叹气] 我看你正准备 像往常一样去休假，
SO, HERE.
所以，拿着。
A CHRISTMAS PRESENT? FROM YOU?
圣诞礼物？ 你送的？
DON'T GO HANGING MISTLETOE.
别想入非非了。 注：原文指别指望我会挂槲寄生（圣诞习俗，在槲寄生下可以亲吻）。
SEE YOU AFTER THE FIRST.
元旦后再见。
AND A MERRY CHRISTMAS TO YOU TOO, MISS PARKER.
也祝你圣诞快乐， 帕克小姐。
♪ BY BY, LULLY, LULLAY ♪♪
♪ 睡吧，宝贝，睡吧 ♪
KIM. HEY.
金。 嘿。
HI. I WAS GOING OVER LAST YEAR'S DUTY ROSTER,
嗨。我刚才翻了一下 去年的值班表，
AND I SEE THAT YOU WERE WORKING ON CHRISTMAS EVE.
我发现去年 平安夜是你值班。
I WAS THE ROOKIE LAST YEAR. THAT MEANS THAT THIS YEAR, YOU GET TO WAIT UP FOR SANTA.
去年我是新人。 这意味着今年 轮到你等圣诞老人了。
[ Laughs ] I DON'T MIND WORKING THE HOLIDAY.
[笑声] 我不介意 节日加班。
THE TRUTH IS, I'VE NEVER REALLY HAD CHRISTMAS EVE OFF.
说实话，我从来没 真正休过平安夜。
I WANTED TO ASK YOU ABOUT THE AUTOPSIES THAT WERE PERFORMED THAT NIGHT.
我想问问你那天晚上 进行的验尸工作。
SHOOT. ACCORDING TO THE FILES, THERE WERE ONLY TWO.
问吧。 根据档案， 只有两例。
A HOMELESS HIT-AND-RUN VICTIM NAMED CHRISTMAS GEORGE,
一个是叫“圣诞乔治”的 流浪汉肇事逃逸受害者，
AND AN 80-YEAR-OLD WOMAN NAMED EDWINA MORRIS.
还有一个叫 埃德温娜·莫里斯的 80岁老妇人。
DO YOU REMEMBER THEM? I REMEMBER THE MORRIS WOMAN.
你还记得他们吗？ 我记得 那个莫里斯太太。
DEAD RINGER FOR GRANDMA WALTON. ONLY FAT.
长得特别像 沃尔顿奶奶。 只是胖了点。 注：沃尔顿奶奶是美剧《沃尔顿家族》中的经典慈祥长辈形象。
BUT I REALLY WASN'T INVOLVED IN THE HIT-AND-RUN.
但我确实没参与 那个肇事逃逸案。
I THOUGHT YOU WERE THE ONLY ONE ON DUTY THAT NIGHT.
我以为那天晚上 只有你一个人值班。
I WAS, UNTIL DRAKE CAME IN WITH THE HIT-AND-RUN.
本来是，直到德雷克 带着那个受害者进来。
SHE DID THAT AUTOPSY.
是她做的验尸。
THE CHIEF CORONER CAME IN ON CHRISTMAS EVE...
首席法医 竟然在平安夜回来……
TO PERFORM AN AUTOPSY ON A HOMELESS MAN?
就为了给一个 流浪汉做验尸？
WITH KARMA LIKE HERS, SHE'S PROBABLY NOT THAT POPULAR ON THE PARTY CIRCUIT,
像她这种脾气的人， 估计也没什么 派对会请她，
IF YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYIN'.
你懂我意思吧。
THE OTHER BODY. EDWINA MORRIS.
另一个身体。 埃德温娜·莫里斯。
WAS SHE A PSYCH PATIENT? NO.
她是精神科病人吗？ 不是。
JUST A VERY LARGE GRANDMOTHER OF SIX...
只是一个有六个孙辈的 普通老奶奶……
WHO DIED OF NATURAL CAUSES.
死于自然原因。
WHY? ACCORDING TO THE TOXICOLOGY REPORT,
怎么了？ 根据 毒理学报告，
THERE WERE TRACES OF PHENOTRIPTICOL IN HER BLOOD.
她的血液里 含有微量的 苯三甲曲醇。
- PHENOTRIPTICOL? - YES.
- 苯三甲曲醇？ - 是的。
ISN'T THAT USED TO SUBDUE PATIENTS DURING PSYCHOTIC EPISODES?
那不是用来 镇压发病的 精神病人的吗？
AND IN STRONGER DOSES, IT INDUCES A STATE OF PARALYSIS,
大剂量使用时， 它会诱发瘫痪状态，
WHERE THE PATIENT IS CONSCIOUS, BUT RENDERED IMMOBILE.
病人是有意识的， 但却无法动弹。
- DEAD. BUT NOT DEAD. - OH, MY GOD.
- 死了。但还没死透。 - 噢，我的天。
PLEASE DON'T TELL ME THAT I PERFORMED AN AUTOPSY ON SOMEONE WHO WAS ALIVE--
请别告诉我 我给一个 活着的人 做了验尸——
- AND CONSCIOUS! - NO. NO.
- 而且还是清醒的！ - 不。不。
- YOU DIDN'T. - WELL, THIS COULDN'T HAVE HAPPENED.
- 你没有。 - 这不可能 发生啊。
SOMEONE MUST HAVE MESSED UP THE TOXICOLOGY REPORTS.
肯定有人 弄乱了 毒理学报告。
OR SWITCHED THEM. ON PURPOSE.
或者是 故意 调换了。
[ Women's Choir On Radio ] ♪ WHAT CHILD IS THIS ♪
[收音机里的合唱] ♪ 这是哪个孩子 ♪
♪ WHO LAID TO REST ♪
♪ 正在安息 ♪
♪ ON MARY'S LAP IS SLEEPING ♪
♪ 在玛利亚膝上安睡 ♪
♪ WHOM ANGELS GREET WITH ANTHEMS SWEET ♪
♪ 天使们用 ♪ ♪ 甜美的颂歌迎接他 ♪
♪ WHILE SHEPHERDS WATCH ARE KEEPING ♪
♪ 牧羊人们 ♪ ♪ 正在守望 ♪
♪ THIS, THIS, IS CHRIST THE KING ♪
♪ 这就是，这就是 ♪ ♪ 基督之王 ♪
♪ WHOM SHEPHERDS GUARD AND ANGELS SING ♪
♪ 牧羊人守护 ♪ ♪ 天使歌唱 ♪
♪ HASTE, HASTE TO BRING HIM LAUD ♪
♪ 快，快 ♪ ♪ 去赞美他 ♪
♪ THE BABE, THE SON OF MARY ♪♪
♪ 那个圣婴，玛利亚之子 ♪
YOU'RE MISS PARKER, AREN'T YOU? I DIDN'T KNOW ANYONE WAS HERE.
你是帕克小姐，对吧？ 我不知道 还有人在。
PLEASE DON'T TELL ANYONE I WAS HERE. NO, WAIT.
请别告诉 任何人我在这儿。 不，等等。
WHY DID YOU COME?
你为什么来这儿？
MY MOM LETS ME SEE THE RABBITS WHEN NO ONE'S HERE.
我妈妈趁没人的时候 让我来看兔子。
I WANT ONE, BUT MY FATHER WON'T LET ME HAVE PETS AT HOME.
我想要一只，但我爸爸 不准我在家里养宠物。
[ Young Jarod ] WE'VE BEEN STUDYING THEM.
[年幼的JAROD] 我们一直在研究它们。
THERE ARE THREE SETS OF TWINS.
这里有三对双胞胎。
NOW WATCH. THEY'VE NEVER BEEN TOGETHER BEFORE.
看好了。它们以前 从未在一起待过。
BUT SOMEHOW, THE ONES THAT ARE GENETICALLY IDENTICAL JUST SEEM TO FIND EACH OTHER.
但不知为何，那些 基因完全相同的 总是能找到彼此。
LIKE SOMETHING INSIDE THEM DRAWS THEM TOGETHER. SEE?
就像它们体内的 某种东西 把它们吸引到了一起。看？
THEY'RE SOFT.
它们软绵绵的。
[ Door Latch Rattling ]
[门闩晃动声]
[ Car Alarm Beeping ]
[汽车报警声]
- EXCUSE ME. CAN YOU SP-- - NOT MY NEIGHBORHOOD.
- 打扰一下。能借点—— - 这儿可不是我的地盘。
[ Starting Engine ]
[启动引擎]
[ Engaging Gears ]
[挂挡声]
- [ Screams ] - [ Grunts ]
- [尖叫] - [闷哼]
OH, MY GOD. DIDN'T YOU SEE ME? JAROD!
噢，我的天。 你没看见我吗？ JAROD!
[ Grunting ] I'M OKAY. I'M OKAY. IT WAS JUST A-- A LITTLE SCRATCH.
[呻吟] 我没事。 我没事。只是 一点擦伤。
ARE YOU OKAY? I'M FINE. COME ON.
你 没事吧？ 我很好。来吧。
I-I CAN HELP YOU OUT WITH THAT.
我能 帮你 处理一下。
[ Panting ] YOU CERTAINLY COME PREPARED.
[喘息] 你准备得 倒是挺周全。
OUR PATIENTS MAY BE DEAD, BUT WE'RE STILL DOCTORS, RIGHT?
虽然我们的病人都死了， 但我们还是医生，对吧？
I SUPPOSE. I ALWAYS KEEP IT ON HAND.
我想是的。 我总是 随身带着它。
YOU NEVER KNOW WHEN SOMEBODY MIGHT NEED ONE OF US.
你永远不知道 什么时候 有人会 需要我们。
- [ Beeps ] - [ Whirring ]
- [哔声] - [旋转声]
WHY, JAROD. I THOUGHT THEY'D TAKEN YOU BACK TO YOUR ROOM.
哎呀，JAROD。我以为 他们已经把你带回房间了。
- WHAT ARE THOSE, SYDNEY? - THEY'RE ANOTHER PROJECT I'M WORKING ON.
- 那些是什么，悉尼？ - 它们是我正在 进行的另一个项目。
[ Buzzing ] [ Woman ] YOUR CAR IS READY TO TAKE YOU...
[蜂鸣声] [女人] 您的车 已经准备好 送您去…… 普莱森特山疗养院了。
- TO THE MOUNT PLEASANT HOME. - YES. THANK YOU. TELL THEM TO WAIT.
- 好的。谢谢。 让他们等着。 - 好的。
[ Young Jarod ] YOU WILL COME BACK, WON'T YOU, SYDNEY?
[年幼的JAROD] 你会回来的， 对吧，悉尼？
[ Young Sydney ] I ALWAYS COME BACK, JAROD. DON'T I?
[年幼的悉尼] 我总是会回来的，JAROD。 不是吗？
[ Whirring ]
[旋转声]
[ Woman ] YOUR CAR IS READY TO TAKE YOU TO THE MOUNT PLEASANT HOME.
[女人] 您的车已经准备好 送您去普莱森特山疗养院了。
YES, THANK YOU.
好的，谢谢。
...TAKE YOU TO THE MOUNT PLEASANT HOME.
……送您去 普莱森特山疗养院。
[ Beeps ]
[哔声]
[ Woman ] YOUR CAR IS READY TO TAKE YOU TO THE MOUNT PLEASANT HOME.
[女人] 您的车已经准备好 送您去普莱森特山疗养院了。
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
我马上就到。
♪♪ [ Big Band: "God Rest You Merry, Gentlemen" ]
[管弦乐《愿主赐予你们平安》]
[ Line Ringing ]
[拨号声]
LAST MINUTE GIFTS? I NEED A LAST MINUTE GIFT.
最后一分钟的礼物？ 我需要一份 最后一分钟的礼物。
DR. FUGIMORA?
藤森医生？
WELL, I HATE TO BE THE BEARER OF BAD TIDINGS,
我真不想 成为报忧的人，
BUT YOU'RE GOING TO NEED TO COME TO WORK TODAY.
但你今天 得来加个班。
SOMETHING TERRIBLE HAS HAPPENED. I'LL EXPLAIN EVERYTHING WHEN YOU GET THERE.
出大事了。等你 到了我再 详细解释。
DON'T YOU LOVE CHRISTMAS?
你不喜欢圣诞节吗？
- IT'S SO CHRISTMASY. - JAROD, I THOUGHT YOU WERE WORKING TODAY.
- 很有节日气氛。 - JAROD，我以为 你今天值班。
I AM.
我是值班。
BUT I WANTED TO GIVE YOU A LITTLE SOMETHING.
但我还是想 送你点小东西。
FOR ME? MM-HMM.
送给我？ 嗯哼。
OPEN IT.
打开看看。
[ Sighs, Scoffs ] FRUITCAKE.
[叹气，冷笑] 水果蛋糕。
[ Sniffs ] THIS ACTUALLY SMELLS GOOD.
[闻了闻] 闻起来 确实挺香。
I WAS SO IMPRESSED WITH THE MAYOR'S GIFT, I TRIED BAKING ONE MYSELF,
我对市长送的礼物 印象深刻，所以 试着自己亲手做了一个，
AND I WANT YOU TO BE THE FIRST TO TASTE IT.
我想让你 成为第一个 品尝它的人。
[ Sighs ]
[叹气]
MMM? OH, NO, THANK YOU.
嗯？ 噢，不用了，谢谢。
MMM. MMM!
嗯。嗯！
IT'S ACTUALLY GOOD.
味道确实不错。
SO, UM, ARE YOU GONNA SEE YOUR FAMILY FOR THE HOLIDAYS?
那么，呃，你 打算回家 陪家人过节吗？
I DON'T THINK THAT'S GOING TO BE POSSIBLE THIS YEAR.
我想今年 恐怕是不太 可能了。
ARE YOU OKAY?
你还好吗？
I... FEEL A LITTLE--
我……感觉有点——
MY GOD! [ Retching ]
我的天！ [呕吐声]
DR. DRAKE? LET ME HELP YOU.
德雷克医生？ 让我来帮你。
[ Gasping, Groaning ]
[喘息，呻吟声]
MY STOMACH! MY GOD! [ Gasping ]
我的胃！我的天！ [喘息]
WHAT WAS IN THAT CAKE? I WENT TO GREAT PAINS MAKING THAT CAKE.
那蛋糕里 放了什么？ 我做那个蛋糕 可是费了不少心思。
IT COULDN'T HAVE POSSIBLY BEEN THE-- WHAT?
总不可能是 因为那个—— 什么？
UH-OH.
哎呀。 什么？
WELL, FUGIMORA HAS BEEN TEACHING ME HOW TO PREPARE PUFFER FISH.
藤森一直在 教我怎么 处理河豚。
AND I WAS PRACTICING WHEN I WAS MAKING THE FRUITCAKE.
我做水果蛋糕的时候 顺便练习了一下。
AND SOME OF IT MIGHT HAVE ACCIDENTALLY SLIPPED INTO THE BATTER.
可能有些 毒素不小心 混进面糊里了。
PUFFER FISH? I'M AFRAID SO.
河豚？ 恐怕是的。
YOU IDIOT! YOU POISONED ME!
你这白痴！ 你毒死我了！
[ Grunting In Pain ] I'M SORRY.
[痛苦地哼声] 我很抱歉。
- CALL 911. - OKAY.
- 快打911。 - 好的。
- [ Cell Phone Beeping ] - UH--
- [按手机键声] - 呃——
I CAN'T. JAROD, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
我不能打。 JAROD， 你在干什么？
- I CAN'T CALL 911. - ARE YOU CRAZY?
- 我不能打911。 - 你 疯了吗？
NO, BUT I AM THOROUGH.
不，我只是 办事周全。
IF I CALL 911, THEY'D BE ABLE TO HELP YOU. BUT THEY COULD HURT ME.
如果我打911， 他们能救你。 但他们会毁了我。
WHAT? THEY WOULD COME OUT, THEY WOULD SEE THAT YOU WERE SICK,
什么？ 他们会过来， 发现你中毒了，
AND THEY WOULD REALIZE THAT I ACCIDENTALLY POISONED YOU.
然后他们会意识到 是我不小心 毒死了你。
AND THAT COULD COST ME MY CAREER.
那会 毁了我的前途。
[ Moaning, Gasping ] YOU CAN'T DO THIS.
[呻吟，喘息] 你不能这么做。
[ Recorder Clicking ]
你不能这么做。 [录音机开启声]
[ Operator ] TELL ME WHAT THE PROBLEM IS, SIR. [ Harry ] THEY RAN GEORGE DOWN.
[接线员] 告诉我 出了什么事，先生。 [哈里] 他们撞倒了乔治。
YOU GOTTA GET SOMEBODY DOWN HERE. LAWSON AND HILL.
你们得 派人过来。 劳森街和希尔街。
RIGHT IN FRONT OF THE CHILDREN'S SHELTER. HURRY. YOU GOTTA HURRY.
就在 儿童收容所门前。 快点。你们得快点。
I'M CALLING IT IN, SIR. IS ANYONE ELSE HURT? NO. THEY JUST HIT HIM AND LEFT.
我正在派人过去。 还有别人受伤吗？ 不。他们撞了他 就逃跑了。
[ Clicks Off ] YOU'RE A CORONER.
[录音关闭] 你是个法医。
YOUR BUSINESS IS DEAD PEOPLE. EVEN WHEN YOU'RE THE ONE WHO KILLS THEM. RIGHT, DOCTOR?
你的职责是 处理死人。 哪怕是你 亲手杀掉的人。 对吧，医生？
DID YOU HAVE A LITTLE TOO MUCH TO DRINK AT LAST YEAR'S CHRISTMAS PARTY?
你在去年的 圣诞派对上 是不是 喝得有点多了？
CAN YOU IMAGINE HOW CHRISTMAS GEORGE MUST HAVE FELT WHEN YOU HIT HIM WITH YOUR CAR...
你能想象 当你开车 撞倒圣诞乔治……
AND LEFT HIM IN THE SNOW?
并把他 丢在雪地里时， 他是什么感觉吗？
HE WENT INTO THE ALLEY TO RECOVER, AND YOU HEARD OVER YOUR POLICE SCANNER...
他躲进小巷 想要挣扎着活下去， 而你从 警察频率里 听到……
THAT HE WAS STILL ALIVE.
他还活着。
YOU COULDN'T HAVE THAT, COULD YOU?
你不能 容忍那种事， 对吧？
THAT COULD HURT YOUR PRECIOUS CAREER.
那会 毁了你 宝贵的前途。
SO YOU WENT BACK TO THE SCENE, BEFORE THE POLICE GOT THERE.
所以你在 警察赶到前， 赶回了现场。
NOW, YOU DIDN'T HAVE ANYTHING IN YOUR BAG THAT WOULD ACTUALLY KILL HIM,
当时你的包里 并没有 致命的药物，
BUT YOU DID HAVE SOMETHING THAT WOULD PARALYZE HIM.
但你确实 有一种 能让他瘫痪的药。
HE WAS CONSCIOUS OF EVERYTHING THAT WAS HAPPENING TO HIM,
他对 发生在他身上的一切 都有意识，
BUT HE LOOKED DEAD TO THE POLICE.
但在警察眼里 他已经死了。
HE WAS JUST A HOMELESS MAN.
他只是个流浪汉。
YOU FIGURED, NO ONE WOULD MISS HIM, RIGHT?
你觉得 没人会 在意他，对吧？
BUT LIKE YOU ALWAYS SAY, BAG 'EM AND TAG 'EM.
就像你常说的， 装袋，贴标签。
[ Mumbling ] NO. DON'T DO THAT. I'M NOT REALLY DEAD.
[含糊不清地喊] 不。别那样。 我还没死。
WELL, IF IT MAKES YOU FEEL ANY BETTER, I'M NOT REALLY A CORONER.
好吧，如果能 让你好受点， 我其实不是法医。
[ Voice Echoing ] BUT EVERYBODY THINKS I AM.
但大家都 以为我是。
SO I'M JUST GOING TO DECLARE YOU DEAD.
所以我现在 宣布你死亡。
AND THEY CAN FINISH YOU OFF. ON THE SLAB.
然后他们 就可以把你 解剖了。
JUST LIKE YOU FINISHED OFF GEORGE.
就像 你对乔治 做的那样。
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
圣诞快乐。
♪♪ [ "Jingle Bells," Off-tempo ]
[跑调的《铃儿响叮当》]
[ Voice Distant ] WOW. I NEVER GOT TO WORK ON A BOSS BEFORE.
哇。我以前 还没解剖过 自己的上司呢。
WE'LL START CUTTING ON HER AFTER LUNCH. WHO WANTS PUFFER FISH?
午饭后 我们就开始。 谁想吃河豚？
THE EFFECTS OF THE PHENOTRIPTICOL SHOULD WEAR OFF IN A FEW HOURS.
苯三甲曲醇的药效 几小时后 就会消失。
SHE'S GONNA WAKE UP WITH A WICKED CASE OF DIARRHEA FROM THE FRUITCAKE.
不过她醒来后 会因为 那个水果蛋糕 严重腹泻。
MERRY CHRISTMAS, JAROD. MERRY CHRISTMAS.
圣诞快乐，JAROD。 圣诞快乐。
[ Chuckles ] [ Knocking ]
[轻笑] [敲门声]
MERRY CHRISTMAS. HE SAID TO GIVE YOU THIS.
圣诞快乐。 他让我 把这个交给你。
HE WHO?
他是谁？
EXCUSE ME. DR. MARLEY?
打扰一下。 马利医生？
YES? I'M TIMOTHY. TIMOTHY RYAN.
是的？ 我是蒂莫西。 蒂莫西·瑞安。
I JUST WANTED TO SAY-- WELL, THIS DETECTIVE SAID YOU IDENTIFIED HER.
我只是想说—— 警探说 是你确认了 她的身份。
WENT THE EXTRA MILE, HE SAID. I'M SORRY THAT IT TOOK SO LONG.
他说你 费了很大的劲。 抱歉 让你等了 这么久。
AND I'M SORRY THAT YOU HAD TO FIND OUT AT THIS TIME.
也很抱歉 让你在 这种时候 知道真相。
I'M NOT. IMAGINE WONDERING A LIFETIME IF SOMEONE YOU LOVE IS OUT THERE OR NOT.
别这么说。想象一下 这一辈子 都在怀疑 所爱的人 是否还在世。
THANK YOU FOR SAVING MY FAMILY THAT HELL.
谢谢你 让我们全家 摆脱了那种煎熬。
THANK YOU.
谢谢。
[ Children's Choir ] ♪ SILENT NIGHT ♪
[童声合唱] ♪ 平安夜 ♪
♪ HOLY NIGHT ♪
♪ 圣善夜 ♪
♪ ALL IS CALM ♪
♪ 万籁静 ♪
♪ ALL IS BRIGHT ♪
♪ 光华明 ♪
♪ ROUND YON VIRGIN ♪
♪ 照着圣母 ♪
♪ MOTHER AND CHILD ♪
♪ 照着圣婴 ♪
♪ HOLY INFANT ♪
♪ 圣洁婴孩 ♪
♪ SO TENDER AND MILD ♪
♪ 极其慈祥 ♪
♪ SLEEP IN HEAVENLY PEACE ♪ [ Phone Ringing ]
♪ 睡在天堂般的安宁中 ♪ [电话铃响]
HELLO. DADDY, HELLO.
[清嗓子声]
♪♪ [ Piano: "Silent Night" ]
[钢琴演奏《平安夜》]
I UNDERSTAND. NO.
我明白。不。
WE'LL DO IT NEXT YEAR.
我们明年 再聚吧。
[ Beeps ] [ Exhales ]
[挂断声] [呼气]
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
圣诞快乐。
♪♪ [ Continues ] [ Footsteps ]
[音乐持续] [脚步声]
[ Woman ] HE'S READY NOW.
[女人] 他准备好了。
YOU KNOW, I ADMIRE YOU, SYDNEY.
你知道吗， 我很佩服你， 悉尼。
FOR 30 YEARS, HE JUST LIES THERE, AND YET YOU'VE NEVER MISSED A CHRISTMAS.
三十年来， 他就那样 躺在那儿， 而你从未 错过任何一个圣诞节。
IT'S ALL I CAN DO. HE'S THE ONLY FAMILY I HAVE.
这是我 唯一能做的。 他是我 唯一的家人。
- WHAT ABOUT YOUR SON? - MY SON?
- 那你的儿子呢？ - 我的儿子？
YES. JAROD.
是的。JAROD。
JAROD WAS HERE?
JAROD 来过这儿？
HE STAYED JUST LONG ENOUGH TO LEAVE THE GIFT.
他只待了 一小会儿， 留下了这份礼物。
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HE SAID TO HIM,
我不知道 他对他说了什么，
BUT WHEN HE PLACED THAT IN HIS HAND, I SWEAR I THOUGHT I SAW YOUR BROTHER SMILE.
但当他 把那个 放在他手里时， 我发誓 我看见你弟弟 笑了。
[ Chuckles ]
[轻笑]
[ Jarod ] "'TWAS THE NIGHT BEFORE CHRISTMAS,
[JAROD] “那是 圣诞节的前夜，
"AND ALL THROUGH THE HOUSE, NOT A CREATURE WAS STIRRING,
全屋上下 悄然无声，
"NOT EVEN A MOUSE. [ Chuckles ]
连只耗子 都没有惊动。 [轻笑]
"THE STOCKINGS WERE HUNG BY THE CHIMNEY WITH CARE,
长筒袜 细心地 挂在烟囱旁，
"THE CHILDREN WERE NESTLED ALL SNUG IN THEIR BEDS,
孩子们 舒服地 蜷缩在床上，
"WHILE VISIONS OF SUGARPLUMS DANCED IN THEIR HEADS.
梦见 糖果 在脑海中 翩翩起舞。
"AND MAMA IN HER KERCHIEF, AND I IN MY CAP,
妈妈 裹着头巾， 我 戴着睡帽，
"HAD JUST SETTLED DOWN FOR A LONG WINTER'S NAP.
刚准备 享受 漫长的冬眠。
"WHEN OUT ON THE LAWN THERE AROSE SUCH A CLATTER,
忽然 草坪上 传来一阵 嘈杂声，
"I SPRANG FROM MY BED TO SEE WHAT WAS THE MATTER.
我 翻身下床 去看个究竟。
"AWAY TO THE WINDOW I FLEW LIKE A FLASH,
我 像闪电一样 冲向窗边，
"TORE OPEN THE SHUTTERS AND THREW UP THE SASH.
拉开 百叶窗， 推开 窗框。
"WHEN WHAT TO MY WONDERING EYE SHOULD APPEAR,
映入 我惊奇眼帘的 景象，
"BUT A MINIATURE SLEIGH AND EIGHT TINY REINDEER.
竟是一辆 迷你雪橇 和 八只袖珍驯鹿。
"WITH A LITTLE OLD DRIVER, SO LIVELY AND QUICK,
那个 小老头 驾着车， 动作 敏捷又迅速，
"I KNEW IN A MOMENT IT MUST BE ST. NICK.
我 一眼 就能认出 他就是 圣尼古拉斯。
"AND HE WHISTLED AND SHOUTED AND CALLED THEM BY NAME:
他 吹着口哨， 大声 呼唤着 它们的名字：
"'NOW, DASHER! NOW, DANCER! NOW, PRANCER AND VIXEN!
‘嘿，猛冲者！ 嘿，跳舞者！ 嘿，欢腾者 和 泼辣货！
"ON COMET! ON CUPID! ON DONDER AND BLITZEN!'
冲啊，彗星！ 冲啊，丘比特！ 冲啊，雷鸣 和 闪电！’
"HE SPRANG TO HIS SLEIGH, TO HIS TEAM GAVE A WHISTLE,
他 跳上雪橇， 对着 鹿群 吹了声口哨，
"AND AWAY THEY ALL FLEW LIKE THE DOWN OF A THISTLE.
它们 就像 蓟草的绒毛 一样 飞走了。
"BUT I HEARD HIM EXCLAIM, ERE HE DROVE OUT OF SIGHT,
但在 他消失前， 我 听到他 大声喊道：
'HAPPY CHRISTMAS TO ALL, AND TO ALL A GOOD NIGHT.'"
‘祝大家 圣诞快乐， 祝大家 晚安。’”
[ Giggling ]
[笑声]
[ Sleigh Bells Jingling ] DID YOU HEAR THAT?
[雪橇铃声] 你们 听到了吗？
- [ Girl, Gasping ] WHAT? - FROM THE OTHER ROOM.
- [女孩惊呼] 什么？ - 隔壁房间 传来的。
- COULD IT BE-- - [ Children ] SANTA!
- 难道是—— - [孩子们] 圣诞老人！
[ Girl ] LET'S GO IN THE OTHER ROOM! UNDER THE TREE!
[女孩] 我们去 隔壁房间 看看！ 就在 圣诞树下！
[ Chattering ]
[杂谈声]
A PRESENT FOR ME?
给我的 礼物？
I WONDER WHO IT'S FROM? LET'S SEE WHAT YOU GOT.
我想 知道 是谁送的？ 让我们 看看 你拿到了什么。
WHAT'S IT SAY?
上面 写的什么？
[ Mews ]
[猫叫声]